Merle Montgomery Papers
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Business Papers, 1942-1983 (Box 3-14)
  - National Federation of Music Clubs, 1954-1981 (Box 6-10)
    Arranged alphabetically by type of materials or name of initiative and chronologically therein.
    - American Women Composers, 1971-1980, undated, This material also includes documents relating to various women's issues, including League of Women Composers, International Women's Year, laws and bills regarding women, and women in the arts.; (5 folders) (Box-folder 6/7-11)
    - Clippings, 1954-circa 1980, (5 folders) (Box-folder 6/12-16)
    - Convention materials, 1963-1981 (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Correspondence, 1961-1981, (4 folders) (Box-folder 7/2-5)
    - Financial materials, 1942-1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box-folder 7/6-7)
    - International Year of the Child, 1979 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - Junior activities, 1960-1981, (10 folders) (Box-folder 7/9-13--8/1-5)
    - New York Federation of Music Clubs, 1954-1981, (14 folders) (Box-folder 8/6-19)
    - Opera for Youth, 1977-1979, (5 folders) (Box-folder 9/1-5)
    - Parade of American Music materials, 1960-1974, (2 folders) (Box-folder 9/6-7)
    - Plan of work, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Publications, brochures (Box-folder 9/9-10)
    - Publicity materials (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Reports, 1962-1982, undated, Includes by-laws.; (2 folders) (Box-folder 10/1-2)
    - Wolf Trap American University Program for the Performing Arts, 1971-1974, (3 folders) (Box-folder 10/3-5)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 1960-1981, undated, (5 folders) (Box-folder 10/6-10)
  - National Music Council, 1966-1981 (Box 10-12)
    Correspondence, reports, meeting minutes and agendas, brochures, newsletters, member lists, promotional and publicity materials, programs, clippings.
    - Bicentennial Parade of American Music, 1973-1977, (3 folders) (Box-folder 10/11-13)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1981 (Box-folder 10/15)
    - International arts festivals, correspondence, 1974-1980, (2 folders) (Box-folder 11/1-2)
    - International arts festivals, planning documents, 1978-1980 (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Meeting minutes and agendas, 1966-1977 (Box-folder 12/1)
    - Programs and brochures, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 12/2)
    - Promotional materials, 1975-1982, (2 folders) (Box-folder 12/3-4)
    - Reports, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Miscellaneous documents (Box-folder 12/6)
  - New York City Opera Guild, 1966-1983 (Box 12)
    Correspondence, by-laws, meeting minutes, newsletters, membership lists, promotional and publicity materials, handbook, financial documents, clippings.
    - Clippings (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Publications, 1967-1981 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1966-1983, (2 folders) (Box-folder 12/9-10)
  - New York Philomusica Chamber Ensemble, 1970-1982 (Box 12)
    Correspondence, brochures, promotional and publicity materials, program outlines, drafts of various materials, programs, miscellaneous business papers, clippings.
    - Brochures and programs (Box-folder 12/11)
    - Business papers, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 12/12)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 12/13)
    - Correspondence, 1970-1982 (Box-folder 12/14)
    - Promotional materials, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 12/15)
    - Miscellaneous papers (Box-folder 12/16)
  - Scribner Music Library, circa 1961-1972 (Box 13)
    Correspondence, proofs, drafts, lists of composers and compositions, memos, copies of agreements, reviews, promotional and publicity materials.
    - Correspondence, 1961-1972, (6 folders) (Box-folder 13/1-6)
    - Proofs and drafts, (4 folders) (Box-folder 13/7-10)
    - Publicity materials, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 13/11)
    - Miscellaneous documents, circa 1960-circa 1969, (2 folders) (Box-folder 13/12-13)
  - University of Rochester, 1942-1981 (Box 13-14)
    Correspondence, reports, by-laws, meeting minutes and agendas, memos, brochures, newsletters, member lists, promotional and publicity materials, programs, investment reports.
    - Alumni papers, 1953-1972 (Box-folder 13/14)
    - Correspondence, 1954-1976 (Box-folder 13/15)
    - Eastman School of Music 50th Anniversary Festival materials, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 13/16)
    - Eastman School of Music miscellaneous materials, 1942-1981 (Box-folder 13/17)
    - Presser International Symposium on Support for the Arts materials, 1972 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - Trustees' Council papers, 1963-1974 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Trustees' Council papers, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - University of Rochester miscellaneous materials, 1964-1977 (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Miscellaneous documents, 1953-1978 (Box-folder 14/5)
- Photographs, circa 1904-circa 1980 (Box 14)
  Color and black and white photographic prints of Merle Montgomery, her family, colleagues, and friends.
  - Photographs (Box-folder 14/6-8)
- Promotional Materials, circa 1960-circa 1980 (Box 15-16)
  Brochures, pamphlets, publicity material, and informational literature on various music, educational, arts, and cultural organizations and programs. This series also contains publicity and promotional materials on musicians, performers, composers, and conductors which may include photographs and correspondence.
  Arranged in two groups: alphabetically by name of organization or program, and alphabetically by name of person.
  - Organizations, AD-AM (Box-folder 15/1)
  - Organizations, AM-CHA (Box-folder 15/2)
  - Organizations, CHO-LE (Box-folder 15/3)
  - Organizations, LI-MUS (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Organizations, MUS-OP (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Organizations, PE-WO (Box-folder 16/1)
  - People, A-HAN (Box-folder 16/2)
  - People, HAP-O (Box-folder 16/3)
  - People, P-TH (Box-folder 16/4)
  - People, TR-Z, miscellaneous (Box-folder 16/5)
- Programs, 1931, circa 1960-circa 1980 (Box 16-17)
  Programs for various music and cultural performances and events. These may include events produced by organizations in which Montgomery was involved.
  - Programs, (4 folders) (Box-folder 16/6-8, 17/1)
- Clippings, circa 1960-circa 1980 (Box 17)
  Newspaper and magazine clippings about topics, organizations, programs, and people of interest to Merle Montgomery.
  - Clippings, (4 folders) (Box-folder 17/2-5)
- Publications, 1956-1981 (Box 17)
  Miscellaneous music, educational, cultural, and arts publications.
  - Publications (Box-folder 17/6)
- Miscellany, circa 1956-1981 (Box 18)
  Miscellaneous papers, including speeches (by others), complete and partial narratives (draft and final), articles, brochures, catalogs, librettos, and materials on education.
  - Miscellany, (7 folders) (Box-folder 18/1-7)